<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <channel>
    <xhtml:meta xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" name="robots" content="noindex" />
    <title>Sam's bookshelf: read</title>
    <copyright><![CDATA[Copyright (C) 2026 Goodreads LLC. All rights reserved.]]>
    </copyright>
    <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/list_rss/197659966?key=CT9AFJGT0_Ay5OmHR1mobm_6SkzbKOcRqvgKYNZ913_DgXUa&shelf=read]]></link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.goodreads.com/review/list_rss/197659966?key=CT9AFJGT0_Ay5OmHR1mobm_6SkzbKOcRqvgKYNZ913_DgXUa&amp;shelf=read" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description><![CDATA[Sam's bookshelf: read]]></description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 09:24:22 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>60</ttl>
    <image>
      <title>Sam's bookshelf: read</title>
      <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/list_rss/197659966?key=CT9AFJGT0_Ay5OmHR1mobm_6SkzbKOcRqvgKYNZ913_DgXUa&shelf=read]]></link>
      <width>144</width>
      <height>41</height>
      <url>https://www.goodreads.com/images/layout/goodreads_logo_144.jpg</url>
    </image>
    
  <item>
    <guid><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/8273908288?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></guid>
    <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Feb 2026 09:24:22 -0800]]></pubDate>
    <title>Wuthering Heights</title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/8273908288?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></link>
    <book_id>32929156</book_id>
    <book_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1478641029l/32929156._SY75_.jpg]]></book_image_url>
    <book_small_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1478641029l/32929156._SY75_.jpg]]></book_small_image_url>
    <book_medium_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1478641029l/32929156._SX98_.jpg]]></book_medium_image_url>
    <book_large_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1478641029l/32929156._SY475_.jpg]]></book_large_image_url>
    <book_description><![CDATA[Emily Brontë's only novel, a work of tremendous and far-reaching influence, the Penguin Classics edition of Wuthering Heights is the definitive edition of the text, edited with an introduction by Pauline Nestor. Lockwood, the new tenant of Thrushcross Grange, situated on the bleak Yorkshire moors, is forced to seek shelter one night at Wuthering Heights, the home of his landlord. There he discovers the history of the tempestuous events that took place years before; of the intense relationship between the gypsy foundling Heathcliff and Catherine Earnshaw; and how Catherine, forced to choose between passionate, tortured Heathcliff and gentle, well-bred Edgar Linton, surrendered to the expectations of her class. As Heathcliff's bitterness and vengeance at his betrayal is visited upon the next generation, their innocent heirs must struggle to escape the legacy of the past.]]></book_description>
    <book id="32929156">
      <num_pages>359</num_pages>
    </book>
    <author_name>Emily Brontë</author_name>
    <isbn>0141439556</isbn>
    <user_name>Sam</user_name>
    <user_rating>0</user_rating>
    <user_read_at><![CDATA[Tue, 3 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000]]></user_read_at>
    <user_date_added><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Feb 2026 09:24:22 -0800]]></user_date_added>
    <user_date_created><![CDATA[Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:56:26 -0800]]></user_date_created>
    <user_shelves></user_shelves>
    <user_review><![CDATA[I was led to believe (by women) that this would be cute and romantic. But actually it’s totally unhinged.]]></user_review>
    <average_rating>3.97</average_rating>
    <book_published>1847</book_published>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[
      <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32929156-wuthering-heights?utm_medium=api&amp;utm_source=rss"><img alt="Wuthering Heights" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1478641029l/32929156._SY75_.jpg" /></a><br/>
                                      author: Emily Brontë<br/>
                                      name: Sam<br/>
                                      average rating: 3.97<br/>
                                      book published: 1847<br/>
                                      rating: 0<br/>
                                      read at: 2026/02/03<br/>
                                      date added: 2026/02/04<br/>
                                      shelves: <br/>
                                      review: <br/>I was led to believe (by women) that this would be cute and romantic. But actually it’s totally unhinged.<br/>
                                      ]]>
    </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <guid><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/8273909084?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></guid>
    <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Feb 2026 07:46:29 -0800]]></pubDate>
    <title><![CDATA[The Odyssey: A New Translation by Daniel Mendelsohn]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/8273909084?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></link>
    <book_id>217293390</book_id>
    <book_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1727512433l/217293390._SY75_.jpg]]></book_image_url>
    <book_small_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1727512433l/217293390._SY75_.jpg]]></book_small_image_url>
    <book_medium_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1727512433l/217293390._SX98_.jpg]]></book_medium_image_url>
    <book_large_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1727512433l/217293390._SY475_.jpg]]></book_large_image_url>
    <book_description><![CDATA[<b>A TELEGRAPH BEST POETRY BOOK OF 2025<br /><br />A magnificent new translation of the <i>Odyssey</i> by best-selling author and classicist Daniel Mendelsohn</b><br /><br /><i>'This may be the best translation of The Odyssey yet. Daniel Mendelsohn’s rendering of Homer’s text is both highly readable and faithful to the original metre. It’s impressive, thrilling stuff... a sonorous new translation'</i><b> - </b>Edith Hall, <i>The Telegraph</i><br /><br />With his <i>Odyssey</i>, best-selling author and classicist Daniel Mendelsohn has created a momentous new work, hailed by classicists and poets alike – a translation to stand with those of E. V. Rieu and Robert Fagles.<br /><br />Setting aside the streamlining, modernizing approach of many recent translations, Mendelsohn artfully reproduces the epic’s formal qualities – meter, enjambment, alliteration, assonance – and in so doing restores to Homer’s master work its archaic grandeur. His expansive six-beat line, far closer to the original than that of other recent translations, allows him to capture each of Homer’s verses line for line, without sacrificing the amplitude and shadings of the original.<br /><br />The result is the richest, most precise, and most musical <i>Odyssey</i> in English, one that fully conveys its oral poetics while bringing to vivid life the gripping adventure, profound human insight and powerful themes that make Homer’s work resonate some twenty-eight centuries after its composition. Supported by an extensive introduction and the fullest notes and commentary currently available, Mendelsohn’s <i>Odyssey</i> is poised to become the authoritative English-language version of this magnificent, endlessly enjoyable masterpiece.]]></book_description>
    <book id="217293390">
      <num_pages>541</num_pages>
    </book>
    <author_name>Homer</author_name>
    <isbn>1802068104</isbn>
    <user_name>Sam</user_name>
    <user_rating>0</user_rating>
    <user_read_at><![CDATA[Tue, 3 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000]]></user_read_at>
    <user_date_added><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Feb 2026 07:46:29 -0800]]></user_date_added>
    <user_date_created><![CDATA[Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:57:01 -0800]]></user_date_created>
    <user_shelves></user_shelves>
    <user_review><![CDATA[A lot more psychedelic than I expected. Book 11, in which Odysseus goes to the land of the dead to see Tiresias and is confronted with the ghost of everyone he’s ever loved, is incredible. Tiresias clearly the best character in all of Greek mythology, by the way. ]]></user_review>
    <average_rating>4.34</average_rating>
    <book_published>-800</book_published>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[
      <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/217293390-the-odyssey?utm_medium=api&amp;utm_source=rss"><img alt="The Odyssey: A New Translation by Daniel Mendelsohn" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1727512433l/217293390._SY75_.jpg" /></a><br/>
                                      author: Homer<br/>
                                      name: Sam<br/>
                                      average rating: 4.34<br/>
                                      book published: -800<br/>
                                      rating: 0<br/>
                                      read at: 2026/02/03<br/>
                                      date added: 2026/02/04<br/>
                                      shelves: <br/>
                                      review: <br/>A lot more psychedelic than I expected. Book 11, in which Odysseus goes to the land of the dead to see Tiresias and is confronted with the ghost of everyone he’s ever loved, is incredible. Tiresias clearly the best character in all of Greek mythology, by the way. <br/>
                                      ]]>
    </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <guid><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/8250510663?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></guid>
    <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Feb 2026 07:24:52 -0800]]></pubDate>
    <title><![CDATA[The Wolves of Eternity (Morgenstjernen, #2)]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/8250510663?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></link>
    <book_id>75293514</book_id>
    <book_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1685352835l/75293514._SY75_.jpg]]></book_image_url>
    <book_small_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1685352835l/75293514._SY75_.jpg]]></book_small_image_url>
    <book_medium_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1685352835l/75293514._SX98_.jpg]]></book_medium_image_url>
    <book_large_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1685352835l/75293514.jpg]]></book_large_image_url>
    <book_description><![CDATA[From the internationally bestselling author Karl Ove Knausgaard, a sprawling and deeply human novel that questions the responsibilities we have toward one another and ourselves—and the limits of what we can understand about life itself<br /><br />In 1986, twenty-year-old Syvert Løyning returns from the military to his mother’s home in southern Norway. One evening, his dead father comes to him in a dream. Realizing that he doesn’t really know who his father was, Syvert begins to investigate his life and finds clues pointing to the Soviet Union. What he learns changes his past and undermines the entire notion of who he is. But when his mother becomes ill, and he must care for his little brother, Joar, on his own, he no longer has time or space for lofty speculations.<br /><br />In present-day Russia, Alevtina Kotov, a biologist working at Moscow University, is traveling with her young son to the home of her stepfather, to celebrate his eightieth birthday. As a student, Alevtina was bright, curious and ambitious, asking the big questions about life and human consciousness. But as she approaches middle-age, most of that drive has gone, and she finds herself in a place she doesn’t want to be, without really understanding how she got there. Her stepfather, a musician, raised her as his own daughter, and she was never interested in learning about her biological father; when she finally starts looking into him, she learns that he died many years ago and left two sons, Joar and Syvert.<br /><br />Years later, when Syvert and Alevtina meet in Moscow, two very different approaches to life emerge. And as a bright star appears in the sky, it illuminates the wonder of human existence and the mysteries that exist beyond our own worldview. Set against the political and cultural backdrop of both the 1980s and the present day, The Wolves of Eternity is an expansive and affecting book about relations—to one another, to nature, to the dead.]]></book_description>
    <book id="75293514">
      <num_pages>800</num_pages>
    </book>
    <author_name>Karl Ove Knausgård</author_name>
    <isbn>0593490835</isbn>
    <user_name>Sam</user_name>
    <user_rating>4</user_rating>
    <user_read_at><![CDATA[Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000]]></user_read_at>
    <user_date_added><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Feb 2026 07:24:52 -0800]]></user_date_added>
    <user_date_created><![CDATA[Sun, 11 Jan 2026 08:49:06 -0800]]></user_date_created>
    <user_shelves></user_shelves>
    <user_review><![CDATA[A lot of this is very boring. Specifically I am talking about the sections that are essentially a Bildungsroman about an adolescent Norwegian libertarian. But somehow still so good? How is he doing this?]]></user_review>
    <average_rating>4.13</average_rating>
    <book_published>2021</book_published>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[
      <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/75293514-the-wolves-of-eternity?utm_medium=api&amp;utm_source=rss"><img alt="The Wolves of Eternity (Morgenstjernen, #2)" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1685352835l/75293514._SY75_.jpg" /></a><br/>
                                      author: Karl Ove Knausgård<br/>
                                      name: Sam<br/>
                                      average rating: 4.13<br/>
                                      book published: 2021<br/>
                                      rating: 4<br/>
                                      read at: 2026/01/12<br/>
                                      date added: 2026/02/04<br/>
                                      shelves: <br/>
                                      review: <br/>A lot of this is very boring. Specifically I am talking about the sections that are essentially a Bildungsroman about an adolescent Norwegian libertarian. But somehow still so good? How is he doing this?<br/>
                                      ]]>
    </description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <guid><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/8251314391?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></guid>
    <pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Feb 2026 07:22:57 -0800]]></pubDate>
    <title><![CDATA[The Morning Star (Morgenstjernen, #1)]]></title>
    <link><![CDATA[https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/8251314391?utm_medium=api&utm_source=rss]]></link>
    <book_id>57799745</book_id>
    <book_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1620081368l/57799745._SY75_.jpg]]></book_image_url>
    <book_small_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1620081368l/57799745._SY75_.jpg]]></book_small_image_url>
    <book_medium_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1620081368l/57799745._SX98_.jpg]]></book_medium_image_url>
    <book_large_image_url><![CDATA[https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1620081368l/57799745.jpg]]></book_large_image_url>
    <book_description><![CDATA[It's a normal night in August. Literature professor Arne and artist Tove are with their children at the resort in southern Norway. Their friend, Egil, a driver by day, is staying in a cabin nearby. Kathrine, a priest, is on her way home from a seminar, the journalist Jostein is out on the town, and his wife Turid, who is an assistant nurse, has a night shift. <br /><br />Above them all, a huge star suddenly appears in the sky. No one, not even the astronomers, knows for sure what kind of phenomenon it is. Is there a star burning itself out? Why then has no one seen it before? Or is it a brand new star? Slowly the interest in the news subsides, and life goes on, but not quite as before, for unusual phenomena begin to occur on the fringes of human existence. <br /><br />Over these days in August, the characters the novel follows will each understand what is happening differently, and all face new struggles in their own lives.]]></book_description>
    <book id="57799745">
      <num_pages>666</num_pages>
    </book>
    <author_name>Karl Ove Knausgård</author_name>
    <isbn>0399563423</isbn>
    <user_name>Sam</user_name>
    <user_rating>4</user_rating>
    <user_read_at><![CDATA[Fri, 2 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000]]></user_read_at>
    <user_date_added><![CDATA[Wed, 04 Feb 2026 07:22:57 -0800]]></user_date_added>
    <user_date_created><![CDATA[Sun, 11 Jan 2026 12:29:24 -0800]]></user_date_created>
    <user_shelves></user_shelves>
    <user_review><![CDATA[What a terrible writer but also so good, really good. He is trying to solve the problem of Death and might well succeed.]]></user_review>
    <average_rating>3.93</average_rating>
    <book_published>2020</book_published>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[
      <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/57799745-the-morning-star?utm_medium=api&amp;utm_source=rss"><img alt="The Morning Star (Morgenstjernen, #1)" src="https://i.gr-assets.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1620081368l/57799745._SY75_.jpg" /></a><br/>
                                      author: Karl Ove Knausgård<br/>
                                      name: Sam<br/>
                                      average rating: 3.93<br/>
                                      book published: 2020<br/>
                                      rating: 4<br/>
                                      read at: 2026/01/02<br/>
                                      date added: 2026/02/04<br/>
                                      shelves: <br/>
                                      review: <br/>What a terrible writer but also so good, really good. He is trying to solve the problem of Death and might well succeed.<br/>
                                      ]]>
    </description>
  </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
